Did you arrange for him too, Mason-san?
The only time I frightened you
was three years ago.
We couldn't have you dying out here,
so I came to keep watch.
Then why did you attack us?!
That was because Izumi-san
told me to toughen you up a little.
You've got to be kidding!
That wasn't "a little,"
we were at death's door!
That's right! How could you have been so reckless with children?
Enough! Stop griping about
something that happened ages ago!
We're sorry!
Sensei?
He's just a child.
He probably just stole his parents' boat or something and drifted here.
If that's the case—
Sensei!
Brother! That light!
He's an alchemist!
Ed!
Why, you...
You turned your
own body into stone?
Wh-What's with this guy?!
Where are his clothes?!
What are you doing?!
He's just a child, you know!
But he might have been
coming after us.
Coming after you?
At your ages, are you already such wanted men?
I'm not kidding around.
Where did you come from? Where are your parents?
I don't know.
What's your name?
I don't know anything...
There, there,
you don't have to cry.
You're all right now.
Man cannot obtain anything
without first sacrificing something.
In order to obtain anything,
something of equal value is required.
That is alchemy's
Law of Equivalent Exchange.
At the time, we believed that
to be the true way of the world.
Those haven't been cooked yet.
Still, I'm glad that you two made it back alive.
Don't go killing us off so easily.
So? Has your teacher forgiven you?
That's probably going to be difficult.
We disobeyed what she taught us.
Even though we knew we were nothing more than one part of the flow of the world,
we became conceited, saying that the world was within us, too,
and tried to alter that flow.
That's something
she'll never forgive us for.
Shoot! Let go of me! Come on!
Let go of me!
Take it easy on me!
There's something funny about that!
Everybody makes mistakes, don't they?
I'm going to go tell her off!
I'll ask her if she's never
made any mistakes before.
Hold on, Winry! That's all right!
Sensei realizes that much.
So don't worry, Winry.
I suppose...
So, what are you going to do?
Hmm, I'm not sure...
About that boy?
Even if he has lost his memory,
Sensei trusts him too much.
But she did take him
to the police, right?
They asked her to watch after him while they gathered information.
I hope he's just a lost little boy.
The meat is too tough!
We'd better not do this, Brother.
Sensei locked it with alchemy. If we open it, she'll know.
In that case...
Al, make sure to put this back the way it was.
Wanna play?
Terrific! Everyone was dead,
so it got boring.
They aren't dead.
They're just asleep.
What should we play? I know!
Look! You played around like this, huh?
So, it was you who watched us
that whole time, huh?
Where did you come from?
Hey, let it go!
No!
An animal's life is not a plaything.
I'm playing! I'm playing! I'm playing!
H-Hey, be quiet! You'll wake them up!
Ah, dammit!
Incredible! Incredible!
You can do that too, right?
Don't lie to me! Earlier on the island,
you transmuted a rock!
Your clothes were also made by transmutation, right?
Brother, your tone...
Al, you saw it, didn't you?
This guy transmuted without using a transmutation circle.
The only ones who can do that are myself and Sensei.
And yet, Sensei pretended like she didn't see anything.
That's definitely weird.
What's the matter?
Try untying it with alchemy.
Take it off, take it off, take it off!
Brother, this boy really doesn't have anything to do with those others.
Al, I remember having seen his face before.
It's as though I've
seen him somewhere...
Brother! What'd you do?!
I didn't do anything!
There's no way I could transmute a person's body and a bed together in the first place!
You're making too much noise for me to sleep!
Hey...
No, no, no, no!
It wasn't like that, Sensei! We didn't do anything!
It's true! Brother is quite the liar, but he's telling the truth today!
Al, thanks a lot...
I know. I don't remember having taught you
any such careless alchemy as this.
Making Chimeras by crossing two lives with each other aside, that is...
Let me down! Let me down from here!
Stop crying!
It's all right.
Can you remember what your original form was?
You just have to remember
what your original form was.
Take your time... Take your time...
You moronic pupils!
What kind of commotion were you
trying to create by scaring this child?!
We're sorry, Sensei!
But we were worried.
What if he was the guy
who came after us?
Just who is it that's after you?
They called themselves... homunculi.
Thank you for always
coming by like this.
But with your new job, are you sure it's okay?
Yes. I work at home,
so my time is free.
Scieszka-san, um, if you're still investigating the incident with Maes...
It's all right. I'm not involved in
anything that dangerous.
I'm not all that impulsive, after all.
Bye-bye.
Well, if you'll excuse me...
See you tomorrow, okay?
Hold on! Just a minute!
Colonel...
Ow-ow-ow-ow...
Aren't you going to Hughes-san's house?
Is it wrong of me to slip over to a close friend's home?
There's no way you can
show your face there, huh?
Not when you aren't even investigating the cause of that close friend's death
and can only think about
getting yourself promoted.
Now look, missy...
These are copies of the materials
that Hughes-san was looking into
right before he died.
The reason that he was killed
has to be in there somewhere.
Congratulations on your posting to Central!
That was easy for me to say, but I don't get this at all!
This is a list of all the external calls that were connected to the Central Command Center.
There's no sort of code here...
To the reception clerk...
To the Ministry of Justice...
To the Führer's secretary's office...
I don't get it!
I can't have you lose
track of them, you know.
I'm pretty busy myself here, after all.
Their master lives in
a town named Dublith.
They might still be there.
Maybe I should go there
and have a look.
It'll be okay to leave the Greed matter to Lust and Gluttony, right?
Yes.
Those boys still haven't given up on the Philosopher's Stone yet.
Arrange for them to have the opportunity to create one once again.
For being the youngest among us,
you sure do give orders like you're all grown up.
I would like to have those boys create a Philosopher's Stone,
but we can't have them sticking their noses into that Ishbal business. Understood?
Why don't those homunculi create their own Philosopher's Stone?
They said that they couldn't make it themselves—
that they couldn't use alchemy.
In that case, this child is different.
That is true.
But you shouldn't be able to reform your own body,
no matter what kind of alchemy you're using, and yet he can.
What's more, he has transmuted without a transmutation circle
just like you and Brother do.
That's—
Al! Not that...
Al, don't you remember?
Remember what?
Ed, you remember, don't you?
The gateway, you mean?
Sure enough,
it's because I saw it...
It was truth, wasn't it?
Truth?
Brother! Brother!
Al!
At the time, I couldn't understand what was going on.
It was as if there was this incredible amount of information being directly mashed into my brain.
But then, suddenly I understood.
Everything about alchemy that I hadn't known up until then...
It felt like I was just
one step away from arriving
at my imperfect theory of human transmutation.
Mom!
Stop it! Let me go!
Please let me go!
Hold on!
One more time!
Show it to me one more time!
The truth was in there!
The thing that I've been looking for!
Equivalent exchange?
What do you mean?
A toll?
Dammit!
He's been taken away!
Mom?
No... This isn't what I wanted...
Al, it's all my fault... Mine!
I understood when I was inside that gateway.
If I acted now, there was still time. If I acted now, I could still...
Give him back. He's my brother.
My leg...
Both my arms... My heart... I'll give them to you...
Just give him back!
He's my only brother!
Al!
By the time I came to,
I was already in this body,
and what had been Mom was no longer there.
I saw the truth there. That's why I can transmute without a transmutation circle
and was able to bond Al's soul.
Isn't that right?
You think of it as truth, do you?
Well, it is, isn't it? I...
It was more along the lines of a magic trick, wasn't it?
Sensei, I just remembered.
I have a hunch that I saw him there.
If that's so, then he isn't human!
He's something else!
There's something I need to check. Everything else comes afterward.
Sensei!
I forbid you to go near
that child. Got that?
Izumi...
It's all right.
I'm just going to go make sure.
Please, let me go alone.
Those boys don't know, do they? How homunculi are born.
Gentlemen!
How good of you to come!
I, Alex Louis Armstrong,
welcome you with my utmost!
Stop fooling around
and get to work!
Lieutenant Breda...
Still, you never know when he's
going to strike. Brace yourselves.
The major isn't here.
Oh, is that right?
He's with the officer assigned to the Court-Martial Office
who has taken over for
Brigadier General Hughes,
and they're off conducting
an investigation somewhere.
Who is this other person
who's taking over for him?
As I recall, it was Frank...
You mean Lt. Colonel Frank Archer?
Do you know him?
He's a man dedicated to his military duties.
That's a good thing to be, isn't it?
By military duties,
I mean that the man enjoys war.
Lt. Colonel,
I'm sorry to ask you again...
I don't know where the Elric brothers went. What are you, a broken record?
There's no evidence that they even went south.
It is evident that they went south.
You have someone watching them? Those brothers are not traitors!
Perhaps.
I just don't have any intention of letting them run around free, the way Mustang does.
For the sake of the forthcoming battle,
you understand.
Sorry about this,
but Izumi-san told me not to let you out, no matter what.
So, where did she go?
Beats me.
She asked to have a boat ready for her,
so maybe the island again.
The island? Why?
What are you doing, Al?
Shhh!
All righty...
There, let's let your hair out, okay?
Winry, sorry, but since we can't come out of our room...
Al? What did you guys do to this boy?
He's terrified of you.
Mm-hmm... Anyhow, Winry, this may sound strange,
but there's something
I need to ask you.
It's about that boy's body.
Al, what are you talking about?
You mean this? I was surprised too.
What in the world could have happened?
At the base of his right arm
and left leg...
Al,
what are you trying to say?
Brother, you said you saw it, right?
His face, on the other side of the doorway?
What's going on?!
Th-This isn't good.
If Izumi-san finds out...
We'll be finished right away.
You guys! Your teacher told you
not to come near this boy, didn't she?
Like he said, we'll be
finished with this right away!
There's no way... something like this could be, right?
It was an equivalent exchange...
Mom's body, in exchange for my leg...
Al's soul, as it was fading away, in exchange for my arm...
It was an equivalent exchange!
Where did you get this scar?
It's the scar from a fox bite...
Is this my arm?!
Wait! Ed!
Edward!
Could it be...
Could it be that that boy's arm and leg are...
Fullmetal Alchemist...
Episode 30: "Assault on South Headquarters"
Sensei,
I am still a dog of the military!